

Phillip B. Mogensen

PhD | cand.scient.oecon
Humlebæk − Denmark

□ pbm@math.ku.dk

in phillip-mogensen

+45 53 82 23 45

Key competencies

- Experienced data scientist.
- Skilled at explaining complex results to stakeholders.
- Strong theoretical background.
- Efficient R/Python/C++ programmer.

Programming skills

Expert R, SQL (Redshift/Server), Python, git.

Experienced Shiny, Streamlit, SAS.

Familiar with C++, PowerShell, VBA.

Other IT skills

Azure DevOps, AWS, Linux (Fedora/Ubuntu), SLURM, Splunk, LaTeX, Computerome, MLflow.

Education

2022 PhD in Mathematical Statistics University of Copenhagen

2019 MSc, Mathematics-economics
University of Copenhagen

2017 BSc, Mathematics-economics
University of Copenhagen

Professional profile

I am an efficient, versatile and driven data scientist with a passion for applying causal discovery methods to drive research. I am a self-starter and I have independently driven deliveries for large corporations on tight deadlines. I have experience with big data, multiomics and high performance computing. I have collaborated with people from a wide range of fields and I pride myself on my ability to make complex topics understandable to the layman.

Work experience

2023 - Senior data scientist - GLX Analytix

- Led a small data team, overseeing all day-to-day operations.
- Built an end-to-end MlOps pipeline using Python, MLflow and Git LFS.
- Significantly reduced labor time of an in-house assay by building a semi-automatic dot blot image analysis tool using Python and OpenCV.
- Implemented and oversaw company-wide project portfolio management using Monday.

 $2022-2023 \ \, {\bf Data \ scientist} - {\it Arbejdsmarkedets \ Till} \\ {\it wgspension}$

- Developed and maintained machine learning models for detecting fraud with public welfare spending.
- Optimized existing batch jobs to reduce the computation time by around 30%.

2019 - 2022 PhD fellow - University of Copenhagen

- Researched novel causal discovery methods and multiple testing procedures, with a focus on scalability for use in multiomics research.
- Taught courses in computational statistics and applied statistics.

2019 – 2022 Owner – JP Statistics ApS

- Developed ML models for Eis Danmark A/S to optimize sales leads.
- Worked as an external consultant to the Market Access dept.
 at Novo Nordisk A/S for two years.

2019 Research assistant - University of Copenhagen

- Researched constraint-based causal discovery methods.
- 2017 2019 Student assistant in biostatistics Novo Nordisk
 - Analyzed data from RCTs and supporting work.

2017 - 2018 Student assistant in statistics - Rigshospitalet

- Worked as a statistician on the research project FC Prostata.
- 2015 2019 Teaching assistant University of Copenhagen
 - TA in various statistics and mathematics courses, ranging from introductory statistics targeting non-mathematicians to MSc courses in theoretical statistics and math.